Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
Throw.
يرمي.
Stop.
قف.
Got money or not?
هل حصلت على المال أم لا؟
I have no money.
ليس لدي مال.
Continue.
يكمل.
Stop.
قف.
Got money or not?
هل حصلت على المال أم لا؟
I really don’t have any money.
أنا حقا لا أملك أي أموال.
This...
هذا...
I’ve squandered all the Li family’s fortune.
لقد بددت كل ثروة عائلة لي.
Who doesn’t know that?
من لا يعرف ذلك؟
I’ll ask you one last time.
سأسألك مرة أخيرة.
If you don’t have money,
إذا لم يكن لديك المال،
you’ll be fish food.
سوف تكون طعامًا للأسماك.
I-I have money.
انا عندي المال.
I don’t have money right now.
ليس لدي مال الآن.
But I will have money.
ولكن سيكون لدي المال.
Alright, alright.
حسناً حسناً.
You, Li family and Jia family, joined forces.
لقد جمعتم قواكم مع عائلة لي وعائلة جيا.
At thirty percent of the price.
ثلاثين بالمئة من السعر.
You bought all the pearls from Wang’s shop.
لقد اشتريت كل اللآلئ من متجر وانج.
You bought all their pearls.
لقد اشتريت كل اللآلئ الخاصة بهم.
With this,
مع هذا،
your Li family dominates Hepu’s pearl trade.
تسيطر عائلتك لي على تجارة اللؤلؤ في هيبو.
You’re the only big player now.
أنت اللاعب الكبير الوحيد الآن.
Now,
الآن،
you still claim you have no money?
هل لا تزال تدعي أنك لا تملك المال؟
I do, I do, I do!
أنا أفعل، أنا أفعل، أنا أفعل!
I have money.
عندي المال.
Then tell me,
ثم أخبرني
how are you rich?
كيف أصبحت غنيا؟
I have pearls.
لدي لؤلؤ.
I have them.
انا أملكهم.
Ordinary pearls
اللآلئ العادية
don’t interest me.
لا تهمني.
I only want premium ones.
أريد فقط المنتجات المميزة.
They’re all premium.
إنهم جميعا ممتازون.
You really have premium pearls?
هل لديك حقا اللؤلؤ الممتاز؟
You’re just making things up.
أنت فقط تختلق الأشياء.
The pearls from Hepu these days
اللآلئ من هيبو هذه الأيام
are getting worse and worse.
تزداد سوءا وسوءا.
How can you offer me premium pearls?
كيف يمكنك أن تقدم لي اللؤلؤ المتميز؟
My Li family has been in pearls for generations.
عائلتي لي كانت تعمل في مجال اللؤلؤ لأجيال.
Others may not know,
قد لا يعرف الآخرون،
but my family has plenty of premium pearls.
لكن عائلتي لديها الكثير من اللآلئ الفاخرة.
Wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة.
Pull me up!
اسحبني لأعلى!
Look,
ينظر،
he can’t hold on anymore.
لم يعد بإمكانه الصمود أكثر من ذلك.
Hurry and pull me up!
اسرع واسحبني لأعلى!
Hey!
يا!
Kawu.
عم.
Yes.
نعم.
Eh?
ايه؟
Did you find him?
هل وجدته؟
No.
لا.
The young master is nowhere to be found.
لم يتم العثور على السيد الشاب في أي مكان.
What should we do?
ماذا يجب علينا أن نفعل؟
I searched so hard.
لقد بحثت كثيرا.
I’ve looked everywhere.
لقد نظرت في كل مكان.
But he’s just not here.
ولكنه ليس هنا.
Where could he have gone, tell me?
أين كان من الممكن أن يذهب، أخبرني؟
I even checked under the flowerpots.
حتى أنني قمت بالتحقق تحت أواني الزهور.
Went behind the rockery too.
ذهبت خلف الصخور أيضًا.
Even checked the bun shop.
حتى قمت بفحص متجر الكعك.
The world’s so big, so many people.
العالم كبير جدًا، وهناك الكثير من الناس.
How can we find him?
كيف يمكننا العثور عليه؟
Make way.
افسح الطريق.
Young master.
سيد شاب.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
Why wouldn’t I be here?
لماذا لا أكون هنا؟
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Where did you go?
أين ذهبت؟
Why are you only back now?
لماذا عدت الآن فقط؟
Don’t mention it.
لا تذكرها.
I got kidnapped.
لقد تم اختطافي.
Young master.
سيد شاب.
I...
أنا...
I know about your joint shell collection.
أنا أعلم عن مجموعة الأصداف المشتركة الخاصة بك.
These are the shells we collected this time.
هذه هي القذائف التي جمعناها هذه المرة.
We opened some.
فتحنا بعضًا منها.
But...
لكن...
The pearl yield is extremely low.
إن إنتاج اللؤلؤ منخفض للغاية.
Ah.
اه.
Hmm.
همم.
With such a low pearl yield,
مع هذا العائد المنخفض من اللؤلؤ،
it’s not even twenty percent.
إنها ليست حتى عشرين بالمئة.
Someone!
شخص ما!
Open all the shells for me.
افتح لي جميع القذائف.
Come on, come on.
هيا، هيا.
These pearls of ours
هذه اللآلئ لنا
come from those pearl households
يأتون من تلك الأسر اللؤلؤية
using inferior shells
استخدام قذائف أقل جودة
Are they just mixing fake pearls in?
هل هم فقط يخلطون اللؤلؤ المزيف؟
Probably not
ربما لا
But there have been rumors lately
ولكن كانت هناك شائعات في الآونة الأخيرة
that shells from all Hepu villages
تلك القذائف من جميع قرى هيبو
have sharply decreased in pearl yield
انخفضت بشكل حاد في إنتاج اللؤلؤ
and the quality of pearls is much worse than before
وجودة اللؤلؤ أسوأ بكثير من ذي قبل
So that's what's going on
إذن هذا ما يحدث
If the pearl yield wasn't so low
لو لم يكن إنتاج اللؤلؤ منخفضا جدا
these pearl households
هذه الأسر اللؤلؤية
would never have agreed
لن أوافق أبدًا
to sell at thirty percent of the usual price
البيع بنسبة ثلاثين بالمائة من السعر المعتاد
Given the current situation
نظرا للوضع الحالي
even if we
حتى لو كنا
calculate with triple the pearl yield
احسب بثلاثة أضعاف إنتاج اللؤلؤ
when settling accounts with the pearl households
عند تسوية الحسابات مع أسر اللؤلؤ
even if we give up ten percent
حتى لو تخلينا عن عشرة بالمائة
we'd still suffer heavy losses
مازلنا نعاني من خسائر فادحة
Young master
السيد الشاب
Should we stop collecting shells for now?
هل يجب علينا التوقف عن جمع الأصداف في الوقت الحالي؟
It's fine
انه بخير
As long as we can still get pearls
طالما أننا لا نزال قادرين على الحصول على اللؤلؤ
and sell pearls
وبيع اللؤلؤ
what you’re worried about won’t happen
ما يقلقك لن يحدث
But
لكن
where will the pearls come from?
من أين سيأتي اللؤلؤ؟
If Li family's pearls aren't enough
إذا لم تكن لآلئ عائلة لي كافية
then we'll use all the pearls from Hepu to make up for it
ثم سنستخدم كل اللآلئ من هيبو لتعويض ذلك
This started because of me
لقد بدأ هذا بسببي
What comes next
ماذا يأتي بعد ذلك
leave it to me
اتركها لي
Stop eating
توقف عن الأكل
Hurry, keep up
اسرع، تابع
Keep up
ابق كما أنت
Young master
السيد الشاب
You’re something, Li Ling
أنت شيء، لي لينغ
You still haven’t paid me back
لم تسدد لي المبلغ بعد
and now you want to borrow my clothes
والآن تريد استعارة ملابسي
Aren’t I stylish?
هل أنا أنيقة؟
It’s my clothes that look good
إنها ملابسي التي تبدو جيدة
I’m going to get some pearls
سأحصل على بعض اللآلئ
Premium ones
المميزات
Interested?
مهتم؟
Come with me
تعال معي
Have you noticed
هل لاحظت؟
that this shop’s pearls
أن لآلئ هذا المتجر
are getting fewer and fewer lately?
هل أصبحوا أقل وأقل في الآونة الأخيرة؟
Don’t talk nonsense
لا تتحدث هراء
I run an honest business
أنا أدير عملاً صادقًا
But lately
ولكن في الآونة الأخيرة
the pearl yield from the shells
محصول اللؤلؤ من الأصداف
has been dropping
لقد تم الانخفاض
We’re at a loss too
نحن في حيرة أيضا
If this keeps up
إذا استمر هذا
the jewelry trade in Hepu
تجارة المجوهرات في هيبو
won’t be able to continue
لن أكون قادرا على الاستمرار
Boss
رئيس
I’ll open one
سأفتح واحدة
Excuse me, excuse me
عذرا، عذرا
Knife
سكين
What are you staring at?
ماذا تحدق فيه؟
Pay up
ادفع
You opened it for free?
فتحته مجانا؟
Hurry, hurry
اسرع اسرع
Here, boss
هنا يا رئيس
Alright
على ما يرام
Let’s see what he gets
دعونا نرى ما سيحصل عليه
Hey
يا
Whoa
واو
So good
جيد جداً
He really found one
لقد وجد واحدا حقا
He actually got it
لقد حصل عليه فعلا
Is his luck really that good?
هل حظه جيد حقا؟
Boss
رئيس
Give me a few more
أعطني المزيد
Give me a few
أعطني القليل
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Not opening anymore
لم يعد يفتح
Pack them all up
احزمهم جميعا
Take them away
خذهم بعيدا
Load them up
حملهم
Why are you leaving?
لماذا تغادر؟
I’ve already picked out all the shells with pearls
لقد اخترت بالفعل جميع الأصداف مع اللؤلؤ
I’ve sorted them all
لقد قمت بفرزهم جميعا
No
لا
Let’s go, hurry
دعنا نذهب، بسرعة
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
To the next shop
إلى المتجر التالي
Let’s go
دعنا نذهب
This is the one
هذا هو الواحد
Get out, get out, get out.
اخرج، اخرج، اخرج.
Where did these barbarians come from?
من أين جاء هؤلاء البرابرة؟
You took all the good pearls.
لقد أخذت كل اللآلئ الجيدة.
Come again,
تعال مرة أخرى
and I’ll break your legs.
وسأكسر ساقيك.
Hey!
يا!
Believe it or not, I’ll smash your shop.
صدق أو لا تصدق، سأحطم متجرك.
No, no, no, no, no!
لا، لا، لا، لا، لا!
We need another way.
نحن بحاجة إلى طريقة أخرى.
You’re something, Li Ling.
أنت شيء ما، لي لينغ.
Shh.
ششش.
So you wore my tribe’s clothes
لذلك ارتديت ملابس قبيلتي
just to use us as a shield, right?
فقط لاستخدامنا كدرع، أليس كذلك؟
Listen to yourself.
استمع إلى نفسك.
If they find out I took the pearls,
إذا اكتشفوا أنني أخذت اللآلئ،
how will I survive in Hepu?
كيف سأتمكن من البقاء على قيد الحياة في هيبو؟
What are you thinking?
ماذا تفكر؟
Tch.
تش.
No,
لا،
I need to survive too.
أنا بحاجة إلى البقاء على قيد الحياة أيضًا.
Sis,
نعم،
should we call a couple more people?
هل يجب علينا الاتصال ببضعة أشخاص آخرين؟
Here, here.
هنا، هنا.
Take it.
خذها.
Take, take, take this.
خذ، خذ، خذ هذا.
Sis, slow down.
أختي، أبطئي.
That looked like the young master just now.
هذا يبدو مثل السيد الشاب للتو.
Young—
شاب-
That makes no sense.
هذا ليس له أي معنى.
The young master isn’t into that kind of thing.
السيد الشاب ليس من هواة هذا النوع من الأشياء.
Young master!
سيدي الشاب!
Where are you, young master?
أين أنت يا سيدي الشاب؟
Yes.
نعم.
No.
لا.
Meow.
مواء.
Yes.
نعم.
No.
لا.
All the shells bought from Hepu today—
جميع القذائف التي تم شراؤها من هيبو اليوم—
if even one doesn’t yield a pearl,
حتى لو لم ينتج واحد لؤلؤة واحدة،
they’re all yours.
إنهم جميعا لك.
Wow.
رائع.
How do you have all of them?
كيف لديك كلهم؟
How did you manage that?
كيف تمكنت من ذلك؟
Family secret technique.
تقنية سرية للعائلة.
Don’t pry around.
لا تتطفل.
You’re telling me all this,
أنت تخبرني بكل هذا،
aren’t you afraid I’ll take you away?
ألا تخاف أن آخذك بعيدا؟
I trust Miss Kana.
أنا أثق بالسيدة كانا.
She’s not someone short-sighted.
إنها ليست شخصًا قصير النظر.
Just these few pearls
فقط هذه اللآلئ القليلة
aren’t even a tenth
ليست حتى العاشر
of what we supplied to the court in previous years.
من ما قدمناه للمحكمة في السنوات السابقة.
Besides, what Miss Kana and I want to do
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، ما أريد أن أفعله أنا والسيدة كانا
is much bigger than this.
هو أكبر من هذا بكثير.
Hey.
يا.
I’m not getting involved
انا لا اتدخل
in your business with the governor’s office.
في عملك مع مكتب المحافظ.
You Han people have a saying,
أنتم شعب الهان لديكم مقولة تقول:
“The people do not fight with officials.”
"الشعب لا يتشاجر مع المسؤولين"
But in my view,
ولكن في وجهة نظري،
merchants are even less likely to fight with officials.
ومن غير المرجح أن يدخل التجار في صراع مع المسؤولين.
Because we can’t win.
لأننا لا نستطيع الفوز.
May I ask, Miss Kana,
هل يجوز لي أن أسأل، يا آنسة كانا،
what kind of business did you do with Manager Wang before?
ما نوع العمل الذي قمت به مع المدير وانج من قبل؟
We did anything that made money.
لقد فعلنا أي شيء يدر المال.
Grain,
قمح،
pearls,
اللؤلؤ
silk and porcelain.
الحرير والخزف.
Yeah.
نعم.
If there’s profit, we do it.
إذا كان هناك ربح، فنحن نفعل ذلك.
Isn’t the porcelain and silk business
أليست تجارة الخزف والحرير
hard to get into?
من الصعب الدخول إليه؟
Yeah.
نعم.
Even though your emperor issued a decree
على الرغم من أن إمبراطورك أصدر مرسومًا
allowing us to trade with Han people,
السماح لنا بالتجارة مع شعب الهان،
all the good stuff
كل الأشياء الجيدة
is monopolized by a few big families.
يتم احتكارها من قبل عدد قليل من العائلات الكبيرة.
If we want to buy,
إذا أردنا أن نشتري،
we have to pay high prices and buy secretly.
علينا أن ندفع أسعارًا مرتفعة ونشتري سرًا.
My Li family
عائلتي لي
has been in business for generations.
لقد كانت في هذا العمل لعدة أجيال.
Our trade routes in the Central Plains are extensive.
طرق التجارة لدينا في السهول الوسطى واسعة النطاق.
Why does Governor Zhang keep targeting me?
لماذا يستهدفني الحاكم تشانغ باستمرار؟
He wants my family’s wealth,
يريد ثروة عائلتي
but what he really wants is our trade routes.
لكن ما يريده حقًا هو طرق التجارة الخاصة بنا.
If these routes open up,
إذا تم فتح هذه الطرق،
the benefits
الفوائد
will far exceed your imagination.
سوف يتجاوز خيالك بكثير.
If you work with me,
إذا عملت معي،
whatever the Central Plains have,
مهما كان ما يوجد في السهول الوسطى،
you’ll have it too.
سوف تحصل عليه أيضًا.
And in between,
وبين ذلك،
no one will take a cut.
لا أحد سوف يأخذ حصة.
Are you serious?
هل انت جاد؟
Miss Kana,
السيدة كانا،
you can check for yourself.
يمكنك التحقق بنفسك.
take your time to consider.
خذ وقتك للتفكير.
All the pearls here,
كل اللآلئ هنا،
I’ll give you a twenty percent discount.
سأعطيك خصمًا بنسبة عشرين بالمائة.
What do you want me to do?
ماذا تريدني أن أفعل؟
Where did the young master go again?
أين ذهب السيد الشاب مرة أخرى؟
If I can’t find him, I’ll get scolded again.
إذا لم أتمكن من العثور عليه، فسوف أتعرض للتوبيخ مرة أخرى.
The weather is so clear today.
الطقس اليوم صافي جداً.
Everywhere looks beautiful.
كل مكان يبدو جميلا.
Buy one more.
اشتري واحدة اخرى
Li Zhong.
لي تشونغ.
Here we go again.
نحن نعيد الكَرَّة مرة أخرى.
The weather is so clear today.
الطقس اليوم صافي جداً.
Everywhere looks beautiful.
كل مكان يبدو جميلا.
Young Master Li is awake.
السيد الشاب لي مستيقظ.
Zhang Ji.
تشانغ جي.
Me.
أنا.
Why is it you?
لماذا انت؟
You.
أنت.
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟